

VAN TABBERT

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

PROFILE

Full stack web and mobile application developer with experience using modern JavaScript libraries and cloud integration. Analytical problem solver with the ability to quickly learn new technologies and languages. Skilled multitasker comfortable working within a team and independently. Enthusiastic mentor motivated to guide other developers to their full potential.

CONTACT ME

t: (817) 908-7911 e: van.tabbert@gmail.com

W: www.vantabbert.com



TECHNICAL SKILLS

Strong: ReactJS, JavaScript, C#/.NET, HTML5, CSS3, Redux, React Router V5, Reach Router, Azure, Node.js, Express, Sass, Wordpress, Git/Version Control, Photoshop, InDesign.

Knowledgable: Xamarin, React Native, Electron, SQL, MongoDB, php, Webpack, GraphQL, Android, Java, C++, Illustrator

CERTIFICATIONS

CompTIA A+ Mar 2021
CIW User Interface Design Sep 2020
Microsoft Azure Fundamentals Feb 2020
CompTIA Project+ Aug 2019

VOLUNTEER

Mercy House Aug 2014 - Oct 2017 Photographer

Girl Scouts of USA Aug 2010 - May 2012 Daisy and Brownie Leader

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer 2

Nov 2019 - present

CarMax - Richmond, VA

- Developing a side-by-side UX experience in React/.NET replacing the legacy Order Processing experience and connecting with 30+ microservices and third-party services.
- Implemented Adobe Analytics integration to increase real-time metric gathering.
- Focus on UX accessibility and reusable design/development for increased user experience.

Software Engineer 3

May 2018 - Oct 2019

Walmart - Bentonville, AR

- Lead Frontend Developer of a nine-person team building a custom ERP system integrating with microservice APIs (C#, Node, Python), legacy applications and third-party services.
- Lead Developer and Systems Architect for React UI Library suite encompassing designs for structural, presentational, chatbot and feedback components with dynamically rendered web documentation.
- Supporting other teams' development projects as needed. I.e. project architecture mapping, specific feature development and application optimization.
- Mentor 5 junior developers with 1:1 development sessions and/or career and goal planning.

Mobile and Web Application Developer

Sept 2018 - Sept 2019

Tabbert Technologies, LLC - Bentonville, AR

- Consulting for more than a dozen nonprofits and local businesses to create websites and applications using React and WordPress (JS/PHP).
- Focusing on reaching customers, donors, and recipients using modern UI/UX principles and SEO optimization for maximum reach.

Frontend Developer (Remote)

Jul 2017 - Jun 2018

Chingu - Toronto, Canada

- Front end development of the original Chingu Developer Network client using React and interfacing with a Node/GraphQL/PostgreSQL backend.
- Facilitate 8-10 week long Voyage cohorts of 350 persons across 75 nations.

EDUCATION

Bachelors of Science, Software Development

Apr 2021

Western Governors University - SLC, UT

Programming in C#, UX/UI Design, Software Quality Assurance

Associates of Applied Science, Software Development

Dec 2017

North Lake College - Irving, TX

Programming in Java and C++. President's Honor Roll. GPA 3.95

Associates of Arts, Liberal Studies

May 2017

North Lake College - Irving, TX

Areas: Accounting, Calculus, Geology and Photography. GPA 3.92